Finding Aid for the John Crowe Ransom Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series VII: Writings by Others
  - “Address to a Cannon” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “And Now Art’s Rising Cross Is Dead” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “Are We Not in Times of Mass Carnage” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “As a Modigliani Neck” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “As Slowly the Dark Muscle Grew” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “At The Logical Wall” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “At The Seed and Feed” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “Belief” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “Blonde Majorette: Close-Up of her Face on TV” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “The Bracelet” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “Bright Pavilions” (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (2 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - “Child at Riverbed” (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (3 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - “Child at Riverbed” (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (4 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “A Child Flies in a Tree” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “Cleopatra” “Contemplation” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “The Creative Dialogue” “Crowd” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “A Day and a Night in the Funhouse” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “The Dead Endure the Ecstatic” “Death Massque for Poets” “Dedicated to...” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “Dialogue for Winter” “Discriminate Cinder Man” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “Eden Ways and Wars” “Effluvium” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “Elan” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - “Elegy for a Gentle Poet” (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (5 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - “Flaxen Light” (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (6 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “Focus in Purgatory” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “The Game of Galley Galls” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “A Goose-Keeper’s Parody of ‘Bells for John Whiteside’s Daughter” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “go-ril-la je-ho-vah” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “Grace” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - “Green Grow the Rashes” (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (7 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “The Green Key: The Drama of Mimesis as Mutation” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Hell on 125th Street Revisited” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “I Am Freed to Praise a Bruise” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “In an Ivory Tower” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “In Memoriam (J.C. McGehee, Jr.)” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Intelligence Under the Puritan Fathers” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “I Think of All the Untidy Men” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Journeyman” “Journey to Headland” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “just when we think we feel we start eternity” “Lady in the Woods” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Lone Prairie” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “The Long Riot Remembered” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Love’s Failure” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “The Magnetic Field” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Man in His Field” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Mass Death at the Friday Football Game” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “To Meet The Lord in Air” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - “Metaphor” (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (8 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “Metaphor” “Modulation” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “Muzz and the Stuttered Corpses” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “Myth is Ice Cream in Redolent Summertime” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “The Necessity of Profane Love” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “Note to Walt Whitman” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - “Osiris and the Sacraments of Erotic Hesitation” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Osiris Burlesque” (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (9 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Osiris in a Taste of Bury” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Pain and the Fig Leaf” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Parsimony” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Philosopher’s Walk” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Pity Pity Pretty Paris” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “A Plot in Indiana” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Procrastinate Players” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Riddle” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Ripest Riposte” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Rise of Individualism in the West” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Roots That Blanch” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Santa Claus” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Sedimentation” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Sequel to Burlesque” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Several Ghosts” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Sound of Eros” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “A Southerner’s Lament for Lincoln” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Straight Lines, Triangles, and Circles” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “To Consummate a Pink Spring” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “To Sing A Moving Round” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Transformation in a middleground” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Traveller” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Why Eden” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “The Windy Cleavage” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Wink” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - “Winter Estuary” (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Manuscripts: Van Tassell, Etta May (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - “Here Lies A Lady (For John Crowe Ransom...)” (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts: Warren, Robert Penn (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - “Dragon-Tree”, Typescript with corrections, published in 1966. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts: Watkins, Edwin (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - “The God of Wars” (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts: Wilcox, Pat (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Impulse” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Still Life” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “To Emily” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Now That She Loves” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Two Small Boys Play in Mid-March Sun” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Evensong” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “I Know A Tree” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “In A High-Autumn Wood” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “To The Lady in Van Der Weyden’s Frame” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Sisters” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Girl” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Angry” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “They Have Always Been” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “Fear Death By Water” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “She Inadvertently Defends God” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts: Wimsatt, W.K. (Jr.) and Monroe C. Beardsley (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - “The Concept of Meter: An Exercise in Abstraction” (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reprints: Abrams – Arnold (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Abrams, M.H. – “Archetypal Analogies in the Language of Criticism” (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Arnold, Aerol – “Why Structure in Fiction: A Note to Social Scientists” (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reprints: Babb – Burke (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Babb, Howard S. – “The Great Gatsby and the Grotesque” “Setting and Theme in Far From The Madding Crowd” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Baker, John Ross – “Ideology and Literary Studies: A Dilemma” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bradford, M.E. – “Faulkner’s ‘Tall Men’” “A Modern Elegy: Ransom’s ‘Bells for Whiteside’s Daughter” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Burke, Kenneth – “Definition of Man” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reprints: Ceserani – Frieson (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ceserani, Remo – “Sulle Teorie Poetiche Di John Crowe Ransom” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Core, George – “New Critic, Antique, Poet” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dew, Charles B. – “Who Won The Secession Election in Louisiana” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Frost, Robert – “The Prophets Really Prophesy As Mystics, The Commentators (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Merely By Statistics” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Frierson, William C. - “Impact of French Naturalism on American Critical (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Opinion, 1877-1892” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reprints: Harder – Kriegar (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Harder, Kelsie B. – “John Crowe Ransom as Economist” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Honig, Edwin – “Re-Creating Authority in Allegory” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Joseph, Sister Miriam – “Hamlet: A Christian Tragedy” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Krieger, Murray – “After the New Criticism” (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reprints: Larson – Nichols (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Larson, Clinton F. – “The Conversions of God” (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Markovic, Vida E. – “Graham Greene in Search of God” (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Nichols, Douglas – “The Narrative of Johnny Appleseed” “Three Poems” (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reprints: Ong – Owsley (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ong, Walter J. - “Wit and Mystery: A Revaluation in Medieval Latin Hymnody” (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ostroff, Anthony – “The Poet and His Critics” (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Owsley, Harriet Chappell – “Henry Shelton Sanford and Federal Surveillance (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Abroad, 1861-1865” (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Reprints: Parks – Rago (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Parks, Lloyd C. – “The Hidden Aspect of ‘Sailing To Byzantium” (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pearce, Roy Harvey – “Wallace Stevens: The Last Lesson of the Master” (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Plotinsky, Melvin L. – “The Kingdom of Infinite Space” (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Rago, Henry – “T.S. Eliot: A Memoir and a Tribute” (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Reprints: Rantavaara – Trilling (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Rantavaara, Irma – “On Romantic Imagery in Virginia Wolf’s The Waves ” (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Rubin, Louis D. Jr. – “Notes on a Rear-Guard Action” (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Shapiro, Edward – “The Southern Agrarians and the Tennessee Valley Authority” (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Stanford, Donald E. – “Yvor Winters: 1900-1968” (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Trilling, Lionel – “Wordsworth’s ‘Ode: Intimations of Immortality” (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Reprints: Utley – Wright (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Utley, Francis Lee – “The Infernos of Lucretius and of Keats’ ‘La Belle Dame Sans Merci” (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wellek, Rene – “R.P. Blackmur Re-Examined” (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Woods, Samuel H. Jr. – “’Philomela’ John Crowe Ransom’s Ars Poetica ” (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wright, James – “Afterword to Far From The Madding Crowd ” (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Unidentified
  - Manuscripts (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Artemis at Aventine” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Manhattan From the Hacienda” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Proteus Part I: Flight” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Pundit” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “The Sonnet Revisited” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Illegitimate Father” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Diana Upon Actaeon” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Streaks of Gold at the World’s Edge” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Diatribe” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Kind of Love” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “The Epicycles of Rhea” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Epistle” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “No Country You Remember” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Orpheus’ Song” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Waves” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “The White Rose” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Captain Jerry” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “God By The Sea” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Granden’s Wharf” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “Day and Night” (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Notes and Fragments (1 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Notes and Fragments (2 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Notes and Fragments (3 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Notes and Fragments (4 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Series IX: Envelopes
  - 1920 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 1921 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 1921 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 1922 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 1923 – 1933 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Dates Undetermined (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Series X: Ephemera
  - Black “Money Purse” (Box 7, Folder 26)